Menu

Search  

New Student

Current Student

Support Services

Staff

Close

Clark College - Home of the Penguin Nation
==========================================

Financial Aid Office Closed June 10-28
--------------------------------------

Financial Aid office will be closed to focus on processing aid packages as we adjust to new federal systems. Priority given for summer enrollment. Your offer will be emailed to you as soon as your eligibility is determined. Please find answers on the FAQs page OR visit One Stop in Gaiser Hall. Submit forms though ctcLink or in person at One Stop in Gaiser, Mon - Thurs, 9am – 4pm. If you plan to start Summer or Fall term, please register for classes asap.

[FAQshttps://www.clark.edu/enroll/paying-for-college/financial-aid/faq.php](https://www.clark.edu/enroll/paying-for-college/financial-aid/faq.php)

[Home](https://www.clark.edu/) » [About Clark](https://www.clark.edu/about/) » [Governance](https://www.clark.edu/about/governance/) » [Policies & Procedures](https://www.clark.edu/about/governance/policies-procedures/) »  Public Records Privacy Protection Policy

Public Records Privacy Protection Policy
========================================

Adopted by the Information Services Board (ISB)
-----------------------------------------------

Effective: June 16, 2001 | Updated: November 28, 2016

Thank you for visiting the Clark College Web site and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of www.clark.edu. This notice covers the following topics:

### Information Collected and How it is Used

### Information collected if you only browse this site.

If you do nothing during your visit to our Web site but browse, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:

1. The Internet Protocol address and domain name used. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet Service Provider (ISP) or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol address to direct Internet traffic to you. This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu); 
2. The type of browser and operating system you used; 
3. The date and time you visited this site; 
4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site. 
5. The website you visited prior to coming to this website, if you clicked on a link to take you here (referring sites or links).

### What we collect if you volunteer information

The information we automatically collect or store is logged and used by Clark College only to improve the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our services. Clark College analyzes this information (the Web site logs) to determine how our Web site is being used, so that we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public.If, during your visit to our Web site, you participate in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following additional information will be collected:

1. The e-mail address, and contents of e-mail, for those who communicate with us via e-mail.
2. Information volunteered in response to a survey.
3. Information volunteered through an on-line form for any other purpose.

The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your e-mail to respond appropriately. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our Web site, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used for research and enhancement purposes. Information from other on-line forms is used to fulfill student requests for information and/or services.

###  Personal Information and Choice

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information.You may choose whether to provide personal information on-line.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an on-line form. You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an on-line form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse www.clark.edu and read or download any information provided on the site.

If you choose not to use e-mail, participate in a survey or use an on-line form, you will be provided with alternative contact methods.

If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, state law and the Federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Registrar as shown in the Agency Contact Information section of this statement.

The Clark College Web site is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

###  Public Access to Information

All of the information collected at this site becomes public record that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. [RCW 42.17. 260(1)](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=42.17.260(1)) states that in the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.

Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of subsection (6) of this section [(RCW 42.17.260(6))](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=42.17.260(6)), [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210), [42.17.315](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=42.17.315), or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) and [42.17.315](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=42.17.315), an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) and [42.17.315](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/dispo.aspx?cite=42.17.315) when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency's disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.

###  Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information

You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the Web-enabled applications that are described below:

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to pay tuition and fees over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the Web, and you will have to pay your tuition and fees in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student’s name, major field of study, enrollment status, dates of attendance, participation in recognized sports, degrees and certificates earned, term degrees and certificates awarded, and honors.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients;
    * (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law.

###  Degree Audit 

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to perform a degree audit of your records over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display a degree audit of your records over the Web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Financial Aid Inquiry

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your financial aid status over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to give you your financial aid status over the Web, and you will have to obtain this information in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit

 Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Learning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records either in person or by mail.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Registration

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, you will be unable to register for classes over the Web, and you will have to register for classes in person or by mail.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student’s name, major field of study, enrollment status, dates of attendance, participation in recognized sports, degrees and certificates earned, term degrees and certificates awarded, and honors.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Registration Appointment 

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment information either in person or by Touch-tone access.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student’s name, major field of study, enrollment status, dates of attendance, participation in recognized sports, degrees and certificates earned, term degrees and certificates awarded, and honors.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Schedule Planner 

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to check requisites while using the schedule planner. The information is required in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to verify your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling into those classes.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Student Address Change

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have to change your address in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Student PIN Change

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your personal identification number (PIN) over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to change your PIN over the Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Student Schedule

Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information. 

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Unofficial Transcript 

 Clark College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person.

The following laws and regulations may prevent Clark College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of subpoena, court order or legal report.

Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, date of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

    Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.
* [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying:
    
    * (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients.

###  Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information

 You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using the information in the [**Contact Information section**](https://www.clark.edu/about/governance/policies-procedures/privacy_policy.php#contact) at the end of this Notice. You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting a written request that credibly shows the inaccuracy. We will take reasonable steps to verify your identify before granting access or making corrections. [**(RCW 43.105.310)**](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/rcw/default.aspx?cite=43.105.310)

###  Security

The Clark College website has many links to other websites. These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on the Clark College website and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. Clark College takes precautions to safeguard personal information you provide through our web services.

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via the Clark College website.

###  Disclaimer

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at their own risk.

Clark College reserves the right to revise and update this Privacy Notice at any time by posting such revised Privacy Notice on the Clark College home page.

Contact Information
-------------------

You may contact Clark College as follows:

**To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information:**

> Registrar  
> Clark College  
> 1933 Fort Vancouver Way  MS 21  
> Vancouver, WA 98663-3598  
> 360-992-2876 FAX  
> 360-992-2183  

**To offer comments about Clark College's website, or about the information presented in this Privacy Notice:**

> Web Development  
> Clark College  
> 1933 Fort Vancouver Way MS 02  
> 360-992-2891 FAX  
> 360-992-2549  

* * *

Follow Us

* * *

Address

[1933 Fort Vancouver Way  
Vancouver, WA 98663  
360-699-6398](https://www.google.com/maps/place/Clark+College/@45.6360374,-122.6509315,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x9abd0099a24c5171!8m2!3d45.6360374!4d-122.6509315)[webmaster@clark.edu](mailto:webmaster@clark.edu)

Copyright © Clark College
